[
    {
        "question": "Base 10 refers to which number system?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "binary coded decimal",
        "b": "decimal",
        "c": "octal",
        "d": "hexadecimal",
        "answer": "decimal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convert the decimal number 151.75 to binary.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "10000111.11",
        "b": "11010011.01",
        "c": "00111100.00",
        "d": "10010111.11",
        "answer": "10010111.11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convert the binary number 1011010 to hexadecimal.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "5B",
        "b": "5F",
        "c": "5A",
        "d": "5C",
        "answer": "5A"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of bits used to store a BCD digit is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "8",
        "b": "4",
        "c": "1",
        "d": "2",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sample-and-hold circuits in ADCs are designed to:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "sample and hold the output of the binary counter during the conversion process",
        "b": "stabilize the ADCs threshold voltage during the conversion process",
        "c": "stabilize the input analog signal during the conversion process",
        "d": "sample and hold the ADC staircase waveform during the conversion process",
        "answer": "stabilize the input analog signal during the conversion process"
    },
    {
        "question": "The weight of the LSB as a binary number is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "3",
        "d": "4",
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the difference between binary coding and binary coded decimal?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Binary coding is pure binary.",
        "b": "BCD is pure binary.",
        "c": "Binary coding has a decimal format.",
        "d": "BCD has no decimal format.",
        "answer": "Binary coding is pure binary."
    },
    {
        "question": "Convert the binary number 1001.0010 to decimal.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "125",
        "b": "12.5",
        "c": "90.125",
        "d": "9.125",
        "answer": "9.125"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convert 11001001 base 2 (binary) to decimal.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "201",
        "b": "2001",
        "c": "20",
        "d": "210",
        "answer": "201"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the decimal value of the hexadecimal number 777?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "191",
        "b": "1911",
        "c": "19",
        "d": "19111",
        "answer": "1911"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the resultant binary of the decimal problem 49 + 1 = ?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "01010101",
        "b": "00110101",
        "c": "00110010",
        "d": "00110001",
        "answer": "00110010"
    },
    {
        "question": "3428 is the decimal value for which of the following binary coded decimal (BCD) groupings?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "11010001001000",
        "b": "11010000101000",
        "c": "011010010000010",
        "d": "110100001101010",
        "answer": "11010000101000"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the result when a decimal 5238 is converted to base 16?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "327.375",
        "b": "12166",
        "c": "1388",
        "d": "1476",
        "answer": "1476"
    },
    {
        "question": "Decimal numbers can be converted into binary by dividing by two and recording the remainders.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the gray code, each number is 3 greater than the binary representation of that number.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of converting a decimal number to its binary equivalent is called binary conversion.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Base is the same as radix.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most significant digit is the rightmost, largest-weight digit in a number.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "When using the excess-3 code a value of 3 is added to each column of decimal digits before it is converted to a 4-bit binary code.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "ASCII codes are used strictly for representing the letters in the alphabet.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "64 hexadecimal equals 100 decimal.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The addition 1 + 0 doesn't generate a carry bit; one does not exist.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you borrow from a position that contains a 0, you must borrow from the more significant bit that contains a 1. All 0s up to that point become 1s, and the digit last borrowed from becomes a 0.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Digital electronics is based on the _________ numbering system.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "decimal",
        "b": "hexadecimal",
        "c": "binary",
        "d": "octal",
        "answer": "binary"
    },
    {
        "question": "A BCD code that represents each digit of a decimal number by a binary number derived by adding 3 to its 4-bit true binary value is _________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "9's complement code",
        "b": "excess-3 code",
        "c": "8421 code",
        "d": "gray code",
        "answer": "excess-3 code"
    },
    {
        "question": "A binary code that progresses such that only one bit changes between two successive codes is _________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "9's complement code",
        "b": "excess-3 code",
        "c": "8421 code",
        "d": "gray code",
        "answer": "gray code"
    },
    {
        "question": "A binary number's value changes most drastically when the ____ is changed.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "LSB",
        "b": "duty cycle",
        "c": "MSB",
        "d": "frequency",
        "answer": "MSB"
    },
    {
        "question": "The binary coded decimal (BCD) code is a system that represents each of the 10 decimal digits as a(n) ____________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "4-bit binary code",
        "b": "8-bit binary code",
        "c": "16-bit binary code",
        "d": "ASCII code",
        "answer": "4-bit binary code"
    },
    {
        "question": "The __________ code is a nonweighted binary code.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "excess-3",
        "b": "gray",
        "c": "multibit",
        "d": "minival",
        "answer": "gray"
    }
]